{"list1": [{"prize": "1000", "question": "01. In the Film 'OMG Oh My God'' Kanji Bhai filed a case against whom forthe damage of his shop due to an earthquake ?", "options": ["Parliament", "Bhartiya Sansad", "Mumbai City", "Bhagwan (God)"], "Answer": "Bhagwan (God)"}, {"prize": "2000", "question": "02. What is the new name of th'e Hyderabad franchise that would replace Deccan Charges in IPL6?", "options": ["Sun Chargers", "Nizam Jyothi", "Andhra Aces", "Sun risers Hyderabad"], "Answer": "Sun risers Hyderabad"}, {"prize": "3000", "question": "03. In India, under which Union Ministry does the (Rajbhasha Vibhag) function?", "options": ["Home Affairs", "HRD", "Culture", "Law & Justice"], "Answer": "Home Affairs"}, {"prize": "5000", "question": "04. According to a proverb, what is said to be (the mother of invention) ?", "options": ["Society", "Problem", "Science", "Necessity"], "Answer": "Necessity"}, {"prize": "10,000", "question": "05. Floor exercise, vault, and uneven bars are events in which sport ?", "options": ["Synchronised Swimming", "Gymnastics", "Skating", "Wrestling"], "Answer": "Gymnastics"}, {"prize": "20,000", "question": "06. Which actress got married to Siddharth Roy Kapur in 2012 ?", "options": ["Prachi Desai", "Lisa Ray", "Vidya Balan", "Sushmita Sen"], "Answer": "Vidya Balan"}, {"prize": "40,000", "question": "07. Which among these is an Island country ?", "options": ["Yemen", "Maldives", "Oman", "Peru"], "Answer": "Maldives"}, {"prize": "80,000", "question": "08.  what has been e currency of Greece sine 2002?", "options": ["Euro", "peso", "Drachma", "Lira"], "Answer": "Euro"}, {"prize": "1,60,000", "question": "09. Which constituency does Abhijit Mukherjee represents in the 15th Lok Sabha ?", "options": ["Jadavpur", "Birbhum", "Jangipur", "Midnapore"], "Answer": "Jangipur"}, {"prize": "3,20,000", "question": "10. which Indian sportsperson was awarded the 'order of Australia' award in 2012?", "options": ["Saina Nehwal", "Sachin Tendulkar", "Sania Mirza", "Rahul Dravid"], "Answer": "Sachin Tendulkar"}, {"prize": "6,40,000", "question": "11. Which incarnation of Vishnu appeared when the demon king Bali ruled the entire universe ?", "options": ["Rama", "Varaha", "Vamana", "Parashurama"], "Answer": "Vamana"}, {"prize": "12,50,000", "question": "12. To whom did Ravindranath Tagore dedicate his book (visva parichay) written on science?", "options": ["C v raman", "jagdish chandra Bose", "P c Roy", "Satyendra nath Bose"], "Answer": "Satyendra nath Bose"}, {"prize": "25,00,000", "question": "13. Which of these ships was not part of Christopher Columbus's first voyage in 1492 ?", "options": ["Nina", "La Gorda", "Pinta", "Santa Maria"], "Answer": "La Gorda"}, {"prize": "50,00,000", "question": "14. What do the five rings of the Olympics represent?", "options": ["Five games", "Five languages", "Five continents", "Five oceans"], "Answer": "Five continents"}, {"prize": "10,000,000", "question": "15. Lockjaw is a symptom of which of these disease?", "options": ["Tetanus", "Cholera", "Plague", "Diphtheria"], "Answer": "Tetanus"}, {"prize": "70,000,000", "question": "16. Bharatpur Bird Century was named Keoladeo Ghana National Park after a temple dedicated to which God or Goddess?", "options": ["Kali", "Yama", "Kuber", "Shiva"], "Answer": "Shiva"}], "list2": [{"prize": "1000", "options": ["Kirani", "Hawaldar", "Daroga", "Munshi"], "Answer": "Daroga"}, {"prize": "2000", "question": "02. What do the five rings of the Olympics represent?", "options": ["Five games", "Five languages", "Five continents", "Five oceans"], "Answer": "Five continents"}, {"prize": "3000", "question": "03. Lockjaw is a symptom of which of these disease?", "options": ["Tetanus", "Cholera", "Plague", "Diphtheria"], "Answer": "Tetanus"}, {"prize": "5000", "question": "04. Bharatpur Bird Century was named Keoladeo Ghana National Park after a temple dedicated to which God or Goddess?", "options": ["Kali", "Yama", "Kuber", "Shiva"], "Answer": "Shiva"}, {"prize": "10,000", "question": "05. With which religion would you associate the practice of Santhara fasting unto death?", "options": ["Jainism", "Sikhism", "Shintoism", "Buddhism"], "Answer": "Jainism"}, {"prize": "20,000", "question": "06. The cricket Test series played between India and England in India is contested for which trophy?", "options": ["Pataudi Trophy", "Anthony De Mello trophy", "M'A'Chidambaram Trophy", "Gooch Gavaskar Trophy"], "Answer": "Anthony de mello trophy"}, {"prize": "40,000", "question": "07. Which of these tourist attractions is situated on an island ?", "options": ["Ellora Caves", "Ajanta Caves", "Kanheri Caves", "Elephanta Caves"], "Answer": "Elephanta Caves"}, {"prize": "80,000", "question": "08. Which of these actress is married to a professional golfer?", "options": ["Chitrangada Singh", "Celina Jaitly", "Esha Deol", "Ayesha Takia"], "Answer": "Chitrangada Singh married to Indian golfer Jyoti Randhawa"}, {"prize": "1,60,000", "question": "09. According to the Devi, Bhagavata, from the tears of which god is the rudraksha tree believed to have been created?", "options": ["Vishnu", "Shiva", "Nhrama", "Kamadeva"], "Answer": "Shiva"}, {"prize": "3,20,000", "question": "10. Which of these is a chemical element present in the periodic table?", "options": ["Eurocium", "Americium", "Asiacium", "Africium"], "Answer": "Americium"}, {"prize": "6,40,000", "question": "11Which of these world champions is a parent of twins?", "options": ["Sushil Kumar", "M.C.Mary Kom", "Vishwanathan Anand", "Gagan Narang"], "Answer": "M C Mary Kom"}, {"prize": "12,50,000", "question": "12. Which of these is not a work of Kalidas?", "options": ["Raghuvamsham", "Meghadutam", "Vikramorvasiyam", "Kadambari"], "Answer": "Kadambari"}, {"prize": "25,00,000", "question": "13. What was the first ministerial portfolio held by Indira Gandhi?", "options": ["Home Affairs", "Information & Broadcasting", "Science & Technology", "Education"], "Answer": "Information & Broadcasting"}, {"prize": "50,00,000", "question": "14. Sanskrit Shabd 'Himalaya' ka shabdhik arth hota hai _____ ka Asthan The sanskrit word 'Himalaya' means 'The place of ____'?", "options": ["Devata", "Barf", "Hindu", "Tapasaya"], "Answer": "Barf (Ice)"}, {"prize": "10,000,000", "question": "15. Which of these numbers is used before the word 'Shringar' to describe a fully beautiful women ?", "options": ["Chhattees", "Solah", "Chhappan", "Gyarah"], "Answer": "Solah"}, {"prize": "70,000,000", "question": "16. Which part of 'Pudina' plant is normally used to make 'pudina chutney' ?", "options": ["Seed", "Flower", "Root", "Leaves"], "Answer": "Leaves"}], "list3": [{"prize": "1000", "question": "01. Which of these names means 'lightning'?", "options": ["Saumaya", "Damani", "Shreya", "Mahima"], "Answer": "Damani"}, {"prize": "2000", "question": "02. Which of these words can refer to 'a fairly low temperature' or 'fashionably' or impressive?", "options": ["Met", "Wow", "Chic", "Cool"], "Answer": "Cool"}, {"prize": "3000", "question": "03. Which of these names means 'gold-like'?", "options": ["Sonakshi", "Sonam", "Sumita", "Sanjana"], "Answer": "Sonam which means gold eye or beautiful"}, {"prize": "5000", "question": "04. Which of these brands of pens is named after highest peak in Western Europe?", "options": ["Reynolds", "Montblanc", "Faber-Castell", "Sheaffer"], "Answer": "Montblanc"}, {"prize": "10,000", "question": "05. What does the 'F' stands for in the Motorsports popularly known as F1?", "options": ["Fast", "Force", "Formula", "Fly"], "Answer": "Formula"}, {"prize": "20,000", "question": "06. Which of these is the name of an island as well[ as a type of coffee?", "options": ["Mocha", "Arabica", "Java", "Oolong"], "Answer": "Java"}, {"prize": "40,000", "question": "07. Which of these personalities is known as the 'Flying Sikh'?", "options": ["Gurbachan Singh Randhawa", "Harbhajan Singh", "Navjot Singh Sidhu", "Mikha Singh"], "Answer": "Milkha Singh"}, {"prize": "80,000", "question": "08. Which actor played the title role of 'Agent Vinod' in the 1977 film of the same name?", "options": ["Mahendra Sandhu", "Vinod Mehra", "Vinod Khanna", "Navin Nischol"], "Answer": "Mahendra Sandhu"}, {"prize": "1,60,000", "question": "09 If you are driving 'Chappu', Then It mean that you are traveling with......................?", "options": ["bail Gadi (Bullock Cart)", "Tanga (carriage )", "Doli", "Naav (Boat )"], "Answer": "Naav (Boat)"}, {"prize": "3,20,000", "question": "10.Which is the least populated state of India?", "options": ["Manipur", "Arunachal Pradesh", "Sikkim", "Goa"], "Answer": "Sikkim"}, {"prize": "6,40,000", "question": "11. Who wrote the poem 'Hum Panchi Unmukt Gagan Ke'?", "options": ["Shivmangal Singh 'Suman'", "Ayodhya Singh Upadhyay 'Hariaudh'", "Suryakanth Tripathi 'Nirala'", "Jayshankar Prasad"], "Answer": "Shivmangal Singh 'Suman'"}, {"prize": "12,50,000", "question": "12. In which edition of the Olympics did women participate for the first time?", "options": ["Paris, 1900", "London, 1908", "Antwerp, 1920", "Berlin, 1916"], "Answer": "Paris, 1900"}, {"prize": "25,00,000", "question": "13. Which of these did Bimbisara, the king of Magadha, get as dowry on marrying the daughter of the king of Kosala?", "options": ["Pataliputra", "Kashi", "Anga", "Vaisali"], "Answer": "Kashi"}, {"prize": "50,00,000", "question": "14. Who amount these was the first lady Air Marshal of the Indian Air Force?", "options": ["Lakshmi Sehgal", "Padmavathy Bandopadhyay", "Nirmala Kannan", "Puneeta Arora"], "Answer": "Padmavathy Bandopadh"}, {"prize": "10,000,000", "question": "15. Who is the singer of 'Pi's Lullby, the Oscar-nominated song from the movie 'Life of Pi'?", "options": ["Mahalakshmi Iyer", "K.S.Chithra", "Bombay Jayashri", "Suchitra"], "Answer": "Bombay Jayashri"}, {"prize": "70,000,000", "question": "16. With reference to genetics, which of these would best describe DNA and RNA?", "options": ["Base", "Acid", "Salt", "Metal"], "Answer": "Acid"}], "list4": [{"prize": "1000", "question": "01. After which of these personalities, one time Lieutenant Governor of Punjab, is a suburb in Dharamshala named?", "options": ["Lord Dalhousie", "Sir Donald McLeod", "Sir Edward Bames", "Lord Lansdowne"], "Answer": "Sir Donald McLeod"}, {"prize": "2000", "question": "02. Kaiser-i-Hind, found mostly in Nepal and the north-eastern part of India, is a rare species of which type of organism?", "options": ["Fish", "Butterfly", "Bee", "Lizard"], "Answer": "Butterfly"}, {"prize": "3000", "question": "03. According to the Mahabharata, which of these characters got married through a swayamvara?", "options": ["Madri", "Gandhari", "Kunti", "Satyavati"], "Answer": "Kunti"}, {"prize": "5000", "question": "04. Which of these vice president of India was earlier chief minister of his state?", "options": ["Zakir Hussain", "V'V'Giri", "Bhairon Singh Shekhawat", "R'Venkalaraman"], "Answer": "Bhairon Singh Shekhawat"}, {"prize": "10,000", "question": "05. Which of these terms is used for a state of political hostility characterized by threats or propaganda between countries?", "options": ["Summer War", "Cold War", "Rainy War", "Spring War"], "Answer": "Cold War"}, {"prize": "20,000", "question": "06. In 2011, who replaced Gary Kirsten as the coach of the Indian Test cricket team?", "options": ["Dav Whatmore", "John Wright", "Duncan Fletcher", "Gerg Chappel"], "Answer": "Duncan Fletcher"}, {"prize": "40,000", "question": "07. Who founded the political party National People's Party (NPP) in January 2013?", "options": ["Amar Singh", "B.S.Yeddyurappa", "P.A.Sangama", "Keshubhai Patel"], "Answer": "P A Sangama"}, {"prize": "80,000", "question": "08. During the start of his political life, Sher Shah Suri was the 'jagirdar' of which place?", "options": ["Rohtak", "Sasaram", "Mathua", "Darbhaga"], "Answer": "Sasaram"}, {"prize": "1,60,000", "question": "09. Which state or UT of India is divided into four districts \u2013 all named after the four cardinal directories?", "options": ["Sikkim", "Goa", "Manipur", "Chandigarh"], "Answer": "Sikkim"}, {"prize": "3,20,000", "question": "10. Who holds the record of being elected to the Lok Sabha for the most number of terms?", "options": ["Atal Bihari Vajpayee", "Indrajit Gupta", "P.M.Sayeed", "Babu Jagjivan Ram"], "Answer": "Indrajit Gupt"}, {"prize": "6,40,000", "question": "11. What was the name of Jain tirtankar Mahavira's wife?", "options": ["Devaki", "Rohini", "Subhadra", "Yashoda"], "Answer": "Yashoda"}, {"prize": "12,50,000", "question": "12. Which of these Indian currency notes does not have the special geometrical shape that helps the visually impaired denominations?", "options": ["Rs 100", "Rs 50", "Rs 1000", "Rs10"], "Answer": "Rs 10"}, {"prize": "25,00,000", "question": "13. Emulsion, primer and undercoat are all terms connected with what ?", "options": ["Painting", "Knitting", "Sewing", "Cooking"], "Answer": "Painting"}, {"prize": "50,00,000", "question": "14. Which of these is the name for a kind of shot in badminton ?", "options": ["Bounce", "Yorker", "Drop", "Bout"], "Answer": "Drop"}, {"prize": "10,000,000", "question": "15. Which of these cannot be the same for two different persons ?", "options": ["Fingerprints", "Skin Colour", "Blood Group", "Eye Colour"], "Answer": "Fingerprints"}, {"prize": "70,000,000", "question": "16. Which of these Chief Minister of an Indian State is an IIT Graduate ?", "options": ["Manohar Parrikar", "Okram Ibobi Singh.", "Kiran Kumar Reddy", "Omar Abdullah"], "Answer": "Manohar Parrikar"}], "list5": [{"prize": "1000", "question": "01. Who did Viswanathan Anand defeat in 2012 to retain the world Chess Champion title ?", "options": ["Rusian Ponomariov", "Vladimir Kramnik", "Vesselin Topalov", "Boris Gelfand."], "Answer": "Boris Gelfand"}, {"prize": "2000", "question": "02. Which river was set as the eastern boundary of Maharaja Ranjit SIngh's kingdom by the Treaty of Amritsar of 1809 ?", "options": ["Sutlej", "Beas", "Ghaggar", "Ravi"], "Answer": "Sutlej"}, {"prize": "3000", "question": "03. Complete the Hindi proverb : 'Ab Pachhtave hoth kya jab Chidiya Chug gayi________' ?", "options": ["Daana", "Khet", "Moti", "Beej"], "Answer": "Khet"}, {"prize": "5000", "question": "04. Which of these lines would you associate with Akshay Kumar in ' Rowdy Rathore' ?", "options": ["Abracadabra", "My Name is Khan.", "I Hate Luv Stories", "Don't Angry Me."], "Answer": "Don't Angry Me"}, {"prize": "10,000", "question": "05. Vijay Kumar Won a Silver medal at the 2012 London Olympics in which sport ?", "options": ["Shooting.", "Boxing.", "Badminton", "Wrestling."], "Answer": "Shooting."}, {"prize": "20,000", "question": "06. Which Country's Head of State visited Ajmer Sharif in April 2012 and announced a donation of Rs'5 Crore ?", "options": ["Bangladesh", "Afghanistan.", "Pakistan", "Iran."], "Answer": "Pakistan"}, {"prize": "40,000", "question": "07. According to the Ramayana, whose flag had a veena motif on it ?", "options": ["Ravana", "Bharata", "Meghnada", "Vibhishana"], "Answer": "Ravana"}, {"prize": "80,000", "question": "08. Which State did P.A.Sangama serve a s Chief Minister from 1988 to 1990 ?", "options": ["Arunachal Pradesh", "Manipur", "Assam", "Meghalaya"], "Answer": "Meghalaya"}, {"prize": "1,60,000", "question": "09. Which of these buildings in Rajasthan was built to provide employment to people during a period of famine ?", "options": ["Amber Fort", "Hawa Mahal", "Mehrangarh Fort", "Umaid Bhawan palace"], "Answer": "Umaid Bhawan palace"}, {"prize": "3,20,000", "question": "10. Which of these must a player hold during a Raid in a game of Kabaddi ?", "options": ["Ball", "Breadth", "Tears", "Anger"], "Answer": "Breadth"}, {"prize": "6,40,000", "question": "11. Which type of professionals are the lead characters of the TV serial ' Kuch toh Log kahenge '?", "options": ["Engineers", "Lawyers.", "Architects", "Doctors"], "Answer": "Doctors"}, {"prize": "12,50,000", "question": "12. 'Time ho gaya hai, pack up' were reported to be the last words of which film star ?", "options": ["Rajesh Khanna", "Shammi Kapoor", "Dev Anand", "Joy Mukherjee"], "Answer": "A.Rajesh Khanna"}, {"prize": "25,00,000", "question": "13. Which of these cities does the Yamuna Express Way connect with greater Noida ?", "options": ["Jhansi", "Agra", "Kanpur", "Haridwar"], "Answer": "Agra"}, {"prize": "50,00,000", "question": "14. Who is the only woman to become the Chief Election Commissioner of India ?", "options": ["C.B.Muthamma", "Punita Arora", "Anna George Malhotra", "V.S.Ramadevi"], "Answer": "V S Ramadevi"}, {"prize": "10,000,000", "question": "15. Which of these beauty queens shares her name with the surname of a West Indian Cricket legends ?", "options": ["Diana", "Priyanka", "Sushmita", "Lara"], "Answer": "Lara"}, {"prize": "70,000,000", "question": "16. Which of these is held annually in India ?", "options": ["Lok Sabha Elections", "Presidential Elections", "Budget Session of Parliament", "Vidhan Sabha Elections."], "Answer": "Budget Session of Parliament."}], "list6": [{"prize": "1000", "question": "01. Which of these beauty queens shares her name with the surname of a West Indian Cricket legends ?", "options": ["Diana", "Priyanka", "Sushmita", "Lara"], "Answer": "Lara"}, {"prize": "2000", "question": "02. Which of these is held annually in India ?", "options": ["Lok Sabha Elections", "Presidential Elections", "Budget Session of Parliament", "Vidhan Sabha Elections"], "Answer": "Budget Session of Parliament."}, {"prize": "3000", "question": "03. Kamadeva got the name 'Ananga' after he was burned to ashes by the fire of which god's third eye ?", "options": ["Agni", "Shiva", "Vishnu", "Indra"], "Answer": "Shiva"}, {"prize": "5000", "question": "04. How many bones does an elephant's trunk have ?", "options": ["5", "1", "10", "0"], "Answer": "0"}, {"prize": "10,000", "question": "05. In which city is the Peer Dastageer Sahib Shrine that was damaged in a fire in June 2012 Situated ?", "options": ["Srinagar", "Ajmer", "Aligarh", "Hyderabad"], "Answer": "Srinagar."}, {"prize": "20,000", "question": "06. Who succeeded General V.K.Singh as the Chief of Army Staff of India ?", "options": ["Gen Tejinder Singh", "Gen Dalbir Singh Suhag", "Gen Deepak Kapoor", "Gen Bikram Singh"], "Answer": "Gen Bikram singh"}, {"prize": "40,000", "question": "07. According to Kalhana's 'Rajatarangini', who drained out the water from Kashmir Valley, that was a vast Lake, and made it habitable ?", "options": ["Agastya", "Kashyapa", "Valmiki", "Parashurma"], "Answer": "Kashyapa"}, {"prize": "80,000", "question": "08. In May 2012, which country's prime minister became its president and the became the prime minister ?", "options": ["Russia", "Poland", "Ukrane", "France"], "Answer": "Russia"}, {"prize": "1,60,000", "question": "09. In 2011, India's first air-conditioned double-decker train started between which two cities ?", "options": ["Howrah-Darbhnaga", "Habibganj-Indore", "Sealdah-Delhi", "Howrah-Dhanbad"], "Answer": "Howrah-Dhanbad"}, {"prize": "3,20,000", "question": "10. The awarding of gold medals for first place, silver medals for second and bronze medals for third began in which Olympics ?", "options": ["1900, Paris", "1904, St Louis", "1908, London", "1912, Stockholm"], "Answer": "1904, St louis"}, {"prize": "6,40,000", "question": "11. In 1860, Which British official became the first auditor General of India ?", "options": ["Sir ACox", "Sir Proby Cautley", "Lord Sallsbury", "Sir Edmund Drummond"], "Answer": "Sir Edmund Drummond"}, {"prize": "12,50,000", "question": "12. Which of these sweets are often cast in various moulds to resemble flowers, fruit and shells ?", "options": ["Rosogulla", "Rasmalai", "Sandesh", "Ledikeni"], "Answer": "Sandesh"}, {"prize": "25,00,000", "question": "13. What does a Kilo equal to, as in kilometre or kilogram ?", "options": ["10", "100", "10000", "1000"], "Answer": "1000"}, {"prize": "50,00,000", "question": "14. Which of these sportswomen is a five-time world champion in her sport ?", "options": ["Deepika Kumari", "M.C. Mary Korn", "Krishna Poonia", "Saina Nehwal"], "Answer": "M.C. Mary Korn"}, {"prize": "10,000,000", "question": "15. Which of these events is described in the Kishkindha Kande of the Ramayana ?", "options": ["Rama meets Hanuman", "Rama weds Sita", "Sita's kidnapping", "Slaying of Ravana"], "Answer": "Rama meets Hanuman."}, {"prize": "70,000,000", "question": "16. Which leader made her facebook debut in 2012 with the post ' I gave voice to what millions of Indians went to see in a President ?", "options": ["Mamata Banerjee", "Sonia Gandhi", "Mayawati", "Jayalalithaa"], "Answer": "Mamata Banerjee"}]}